<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>300 Block Figueroa &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/figueroa/300-block-figueroa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 01:36:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>300 Block Figueroa &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Know Your Bunker Hill B-Girls</title>
		<link>/bgirl-bunkerhill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 12:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Figueroa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b-girl ordinance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B-Girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Imperial Hotel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Ruth Winters, 31, of 350 S. Figueroa (site of the Bowman brothers&#8217; asphyxiation by cyanide gas poisoning), an angular blonde with a naughty smile and a way with the fellas. Despite her considerable charms, Ruth is on of the most detested women on Bunker Hill, or at least she is if you judge her &#8230; <a href="/bgirl-bunkerhill/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Know Your Bunker Hill B-Girls"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meet Ruth Winters, 31, of 350 S. Figueroa (<a href="/node/138" title="bowman" target="_blank" rel="noopener">site of the Bowman brothers&#8217; asphyxiation by cyanide gas poisoning</a>), an angular blonde with a naughty smile and a way with the fellas.  Despite her considerable charms, Ruth is on of the most detested women on Bunker Hill, or at least she is if you judge her by the names bestowed upon her by the <i>Times</i> and the thick stack of hysterical city ordinances set forth to curb her profession.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3165/2606100535_d706c671a1.jpg" alt="ruth" height="325" width="500" /></p>
<p>Yes, Ruth is one of those &quot;harpies of Main Street,&quot; a B-girl at Marco&#8217;s Cafe at 513 S. Main, and Ruth is one of the best in the business (she&#8217;s the one with the world-weary eyes sitting in the front row, above).</p>
<p>When Marco&#8217;s makes a new hire, bartender Patsy Figlio always tells the girls to follow the &quot;experienced bust-out girl&quot; Ruth&#8217;s lead.  Pick your mark, clean out his wallet, and get rid of him fast.  And if he leaves with so much as a dime in his pocket, you&#8217;d better believe you&#8217;ll catch hell from Patsy.</p>
<p>Marco&#8217;s owner Louis Lobel told the girls to lay low when the heat was on, and Patsy made sure they worked the crowd hard when it wasn&#8217;t, and the whole thing works out just grand provided that the poor sap with the empty wallet is too embarrassed to let on to anyone that he got fleeced.  </p>
<p>But then Marine Sergeant William R. Okerman decided to visit Marco&#8217;s with $10 in cash, and 6 $20 traveler&#8217;s checks in his pocket.  Ruth moved in, embracing Okerman as he entered the bar and asking him how long since he&#8217;d had a woman.  What happened next was all a blur.  Ruth teased, Patsy poured champagne cocktails, and in a scant 30 minutes, the pair had taken Okerman for all he had.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3217/2606100403_e0074bfd4b.jpg" alt="convictions" height="152" width="378" /><br />
The shameless Sgt. Okerman made a complaint to the police, right around the same time that Kathleen Krischenowski, a former Marco&#8217;s waitress, went in to apply for a job.  She was horrified by what she saw, and connected with the LAPD vice detail.  She and two other waitresses turned undercover informant, and told the police what was going on at Marco&#8217;s.</p>
<p>Their reports led to the arrests of Figlio, Lobel, Winters, and another b-girl, Beverly Reed.  They were charged with violation of 8 municipal laws, including indecent exposure, being lewd and dissolute, and conspiracy to violate the city&#8217;s b-girl ordinance, including 44 overt acts too filthy to print.</p>
<p>It was the first time that the District Attorney&#8217;s office had sought felony charges in a case involving violation of the b-girl ordinance, which had been in effect since 1939 (and drastically expanded after b-girls moved their trade to soda shops).</p>
<p>In the end, all four entered guilty pleas, though Winters and Reed were allowed to plead to misdemeanor charges.  Lobel and Figlio were sentenced to 3 years in Chino, while the women faced 6 months in the city jail.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Death At the Imperial Hotel:  350 South Figueroa</title>
		<link>/death-at-the-imperial-hotel-350-south-figueroa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Figueroa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accidental death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exterminators]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[November 16, 1931 This morning, Gene Bowman, 15, and his brother Earl, 22, decided to sleep late after their mother departed for work. In the apartment directly beneath them, R.V. Darby, the Mayor of Inglewood, president of the Federated Church Brotherhoods of Los Angeles, and owner of Kilz Exterminator Company was conducting a routine fumigation &#8230; <a href="/death-at-the-imperial-hotel-350-south-figueroa/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Death At the Imperial Hotel:  350 South Figueroa"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>November 16, 1931</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3162/2566942918_c1339abfb3_m.jpg" alt="imperialhotel" align="left" height="240" width="226" /><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2166/2566119095_2e21daee0d.jpg" alt="bowmans" align="right" height="500" width="118" />This morning, Gene Bowman, 15, and his brother Earl, 22, decided to sleep late after their mother departed for work.</p>
<p>In the apartment directly beneath them, R.V. Darby, the Mayor of Inglewood, president of the Federated Church Brotherhoods of Los Angeles, and owner of Kilz Exterminator Company was conducting a routine fumigation for bed bugs.</p>
<p>As always, he had notified the Health Department, and given written and verbal notice to all occupants of the building, asking them to leave their rooms and open the windows.  And as always, he was using cyanide gas.</p>
<p>While Darby worked, unbeknownst to him, deadly gas was seeping up into the Bowman&#8217;s apartment through a small hole in the floor around a steam pipe.  Both brothers were asphyxiated while they slept.</p>
<p>Darby&#8217;s license was temporarily suspended while a manslaughter complaint was brought before a grand jury to determine whether the Bowmans&#8217; deaths were caused by negligence on Darby&#8217;s part.  More than twenty witnesses testified, and on December 1, Darby was exonerated, the jury stating that the deaths were a tragic accident, but that Darby had taken all possible precautions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No Place for a Child:  The Collapse of the Vanderbilt</title>
		<link>/no-place-for-a-child-the-collapse-of-the-vanderbilt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 09:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Figueroa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unsafe buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanderbilt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 334 South Figueroa It is unlikely that the overcrowded, structurally unsound, 5-story Vanderbilt apartment-hotel at 334 S. Figueroa was a happy home for many of its tenants. However, children living in, or even passing by, the ramshackle building seemed to fare particularly badly. On April 5, 1939, 18-month-old Harvey Fish fell from a fourth &#8230; <a href="/no-place-for-a-child-the-collapse-of-the-vanderbilt/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "No Place for a Child:  The Collapse of the Vanderbilt"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location:  334 South Figueroa</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3175/2547778300_11ba59ca99.jpg" alt="vanderbilt" align="left" height="400" width="325" /></p>
<p>It is unlikely that the overcrowded, structurally unsound, 5-story Vanderbilt apartment-hotel at 334 S. Figueroa was a happy home for many of its tenants. However, children living in, or even passing by, the ramshackle building seemed to fare particularly badly. On April 5, 1939, 18-month-old Harvey Fish fell from a fourth story window, landing at the feet of his mother who was standing on the sidewalk below. The child suffered a fractured skull, and died later that day. 6-year-old Anna Lee Norton fell five stories shortly after Christmas in 1952. While playing on the apartment balcony, Anna lost her balance and crashed through a loose board, falling on a paved alleyway. Perhaps this should have been a sign to the Department of<br />
Building and Safety and the CRA that the building was in trouble.</p>
<p>Other incidents at the Vanderbilt could be chalked up to sad or unfortunate chance.  In 1949, Robert Lee Gordon, age 6, was killed when he darted out from between two cars parked in front of the building.  And in 1955, 1-year-old Gloria Howard was reunited with her family, residents at the Vanderbilt, after a harrowing evening in juvie.  Lucille Parker, 33, wandered into a bar with the child, saying Gloria had been &quot;given&quot; to her in another local bar.  The child&#8217;s <img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3020/2546955733_39406425ca_m.jpg" alt="wisecarver" align="right" height="240" width="193" />father, William Howard, later reported that he&#8217;d left a very intoxicated Lucille and his daughter alone in a car while he made a phone call.  When he returned, the car was missing, as were Lucille and Gloria.</p>
<p>The most bizarre story of child endangerment at the Vanderbilt brings us to 1945, when Elaine Wisecarver was charged with contributing to the delinquency of a minor after abandoning her 3-year-old daughter with the building manager.  It wasn&#8217;t the first time Wisecarver earned this charge.  The previous year, the 22-year-old woman had eloped to Yuma with a 14-year-old boy, Ellsworth (Sonny) Wisecarver.  The marriage was later annulled, and Wisecarver was sentenced to 3 years probation.</p>
<p>However, on the evening of March 3, 1959, the Vanderbilt&#8217;s legacy came to an end in dramatic fashion when rotted underpinnings caused the floor joists to slip, and the 48-year-old building to slide off of its foundation, moving 3 feet sideways and dropping 2 feet.  The side walls buckled, and plaster rained down on the buildings occupants, most of whom were at home at the time.  In all, 200 of the hotel&#8217;s residents, 70 of them children, evacuated the building.  One man was trapped in his apartment, but miraculously, only three people suffered injuries, all of them minor.  In the days leading up to the collapse, several residents had complained to the building manager that they had trouble opening and closing their apartment doors.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3142/2547778214_8623fda6ef_o.jpg" alt="collapse" align="left" height="72" width="338" /><br />
The Red Cross immediately set up at the Fremont Grammar School, where approximately 40 adults and 60 children sought shelter.</p>
<p>Though the collapse came as a surprise to the Vanderbilt&#8217;s tenants, the building had actually been inspected a few weeks earlier and declared a hazard by the Department of Building and Safety.  A hearing was being scheduled where the building&#8217;s owners would have to show cause why it should not be demolished.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3048/2547781234_b9fa9196f4.jpg" alt="vanderbilt2" height="395" width="500" /></p>
<p>Following the collapse, the building&#8217;s condition was downgraded to &quot;immediate hazard,&quot; and demolition was scheduled.  In fact, the building was declared so unsafe that no one was initially permitted to enter it, including the wrecking crew.</p>
<p>In the aftermath, the City Council asked Mayor Poulson to &quot;define specifically the CRA&#8217;s activities,&quot; and to meet with its building and safety commission to discuss CRA procedure.  This came as a result of the general manager of the Department and Building and Safety, Gilbert Morris&#8217;s report to the Council that the CRA had told his people to &quot;keep out&quot; of Bunker Hill.  The Department also reported that the CRA had brought routine inspections of Bunker Hill properties to a standstill, after a &quot;request&quot; that these inspections only be carried out in response to specific complaints.</p>
<p>Councilman Edward Roybal stated, &quot;I would like to put a stop to the dictatorial activities of the CRA.&quot;</p>
<p>William H. Claire, a CRA spokesperson, denied allegations that the agency had neglected the health and safety of residents, saying, &quot;We in the Community Redevelopment Agency are very interested in what happens to the people in our project.&quot;</p>
<p><i>Images of the Vanderbilt courtesy of the Los Angeles Public Library Photo Collection</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
