<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>teen runaways &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.onbunkerhill.org/tag/teen_runaways/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 18:42:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>teen runaways &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Tough Kid</title>
		<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/atoughkid/</link>
					<comments>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/atoughkid/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 16:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hope Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delinquency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen runaways]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 336 South Flower Street Date: January 28, 1932 Raymond Seccord, a 15-year-old Vancouver runaway, flipped out in City Hall&#8217;s juvenile court today after being busted in front of the above address. Refusing to answer any questions, he upended tables, lobbed an inkwell out the window and bit and scratched four detectives as they tried &#8230; <a href="https://www.onbunkerhill.org/atoughkid/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Tough Kid"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location: 336 South Flower Street<br />
Date: January 28, 1932</p>
<p>Raymond Seccord, a 15-year-old Vancouver runaway, flipped out in City Hall&#8217;s juvenile court today after being busted in front of the above address. Refusing to answer any questions, he upended tables, lobbed an inkwell out the window and bit and scratched four detectives as they tried to tackle him. Seccord sneered &quot;I&#8217;m plenty tough. I&#8217;ll probably hang for killing a copper.&quot; Suitably impressed, Judge Blake sent him to County Jail instead of Juvenile Hall, and we will hear no more of this plucky fellow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/atoughkid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Susie Miller on the Loose</title>
		<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/susiemiller/</link>
					<comments>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/susiemiller/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 12:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[200 Block Flower Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[200 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Telephone Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen runaways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[young love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date: July 3, 1904 Location: 200 Block of Flower Street 15-year-old Susie Miller was a pretty brunette with a vivacious disposition who loved to play the violin. She also loved Willie Miller, a 15-year-old butcher&#8217;s apprentice, and he loved her &#8212; the two were already talking about marriage. But Susie&#8217;s parents, Mr. and Mrs. Samuel &#8230; <a href="https://www.onbunkerhill.org/susiemiller/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Susie Miller on the Loose"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Date:  July 3, 1904 <br />
Location:  200 Block of Flower Street</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3222/2470089966_42a72475e3_m.jpg" width="240" height="57" align="left" alt="susie1" />15-year-old Susie Miller was a pretty brunette with a vivacious disposition who loved to play the violin.  She also loved Willie Miller, a 15-year-old butcher&#8217;s apprentice, and he loved her &#8212; the two were already talking about marriage.  But Susie&#8217;s parents, Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Miller disapproved of the match so strongly that they uprooted the family from their home in San Francisco and moved to Los Angeles in the hopes of squashing the love affair.</p>
<p>The family settled in at a pretty little yellow bungalow on the southwest corner of Flower and Second, and Susie&#8217;s brothers quickly found work &#8212; although the <i>Times</i> was quick to point out that they only took jobs to occupy their time, not because they needed the money.  Samuel Miller was somehow affiliated with the streetcar business in San Francisco and described as &quot;a man in good circumstances.&quot;  Even little Susie got in on the fun, taking a job as an operator at the Home Telephone Company, just down the street.</p>
<p>And then, on the morning of July 3, 1904, Susie Miller disappeared.</p>
<p>She told her mother that she&#8217;d asked to work the 6 a.m. shift at the telephone office in order to have the 4th of July off, and left home at 5:30 that morning.  However, when Susie didn&#8217;t come home for lunch, Mrs. Miller began to worry.  She called the telephone office and was informed that Susie had, in fact, tendered her resignation on June 28, and that there was no 6 a.m. Sunday shift.  The family began to panic, and called police to report her missing.  However, they just as quickly lied and told the police that she&#8217;d returned home, not wanting the story to be reported in the paper.</p>
<p>By July 5, there was still no word from Susie, and they decided to come clean.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2119/2470090000_273e5191cd_m.jpg" width="240" height="142" align="right" alt="susie2" /><br />
Yes, there was Willie in San Francisco, but Susie also had another beau in the wings, a man named Harry, last name unknown.  Mrs. Miller said, &quot;Susie met him over the telephone in conversation to begin with and afterwards saw him and told me he was an awfully pretty boy and that she could almost love him.&quot;  All they knew about Harry was that he claimed to be from San Diego, and that his father owned a gold mine.  Their suspicions were heightened when Willie sent a telegram from San Francisco saying he had not seen Susie.</p>
<p>Millie Leach, one of Susie&#8217;s co-workers at the Home Telephone Company, told police that she&#8217;d accompanied Susie to the train station that Sunday morning.  Susie told her she was going to San Diego, but when she purchased her ticket, Millie swore she heard her say, &quot;Frisco.&quot;</p>
<p>So, where was she?  Had she run off with the derelict son of a gold miner, eloped with her hometown sweetheart, or fallen prey to a worse fate?</p>
<p>The <i>Times</i> wrote, &quot;The scheming of a Sherlock Holmes could not have more successfully covered her tracks.&quot;</p>
<p>But where police and reporters alike were stumped, Susie&#8217;s family rose to the occasion and worked to track her down.  Samuel Miller went to San Francisco, and submitted young Willie to some hard questioning, during which the boy cracked.  Susie had gone to a San Francisco hotel owned by her aunt, a woman with whom the family did not keep in touch.  Once she heard her father was on the way, she crossed the bay to stay at the home of another aunt in Vallejo.</p>
<p>After being recovered and returned safely home to Los Angeles, Susie explained herself saying that she meant to write home, but after taking off, it seemed like &quot;a good joke&quot; to let her family wonder where she was.  Then, once the police got involved, she was too scared to tell them where she was.  Outsmarting the LAPD is one thing, but dear old dad is quite another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/susiemiller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
