<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>medicine &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/medicine/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 02:11:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>medicine &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Keep them Medical Advancements Rollin</title>
		<link>/hotelrollin/</link>
					<comments>/hotelrollin/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 21:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[200 Block Flower Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[200 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bar fights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flower Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LAPD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shooting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surgery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thomas Major Jr., 34, a logger by profession, down from Vancouver to take in the town. He was in the barroom at the Rollin Hotel, Third and Flower, when the cops came in to investigate a brawl, January 24, 1960. They have a funny way of doing things up in British Columbia, apparently, for as &#8230; <a href="/hotelrollin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Keep them Medical Advancements Rollin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3403/3208041899_8ae696f442_o.gif" alt="keeprollinrollinrollin" height="563" width="570" /><br />
Thomas Major Jr., 34, a logger by profession, down from Vancouver to take in the town.  He was in the barroom at the Rollin Hotel, Third and Flower, when the cops came in to investigate a brawl, January 24, 1960.  They have a funny way of doing things up in British Columbia, apparently, for as the bulls were bracing some other bar patron, Major pulled out a gun, pointed it at the cops‘ backs, and began pulling the trigger.  The cops heard the click-click of two empty chambers, turned, and fired seven shots at Major.</p>
<p>Major was hit seven times, taking four in the abdomen.  Detectives Pailing and Buckland, with Municipal Judge Griffith in tow, made a visit to Major‘s bed in the prison ward at General Hospital, where they charged him with two counts of assault with intent to commit murder and one of violating the deadly weapons control law.</p>
<p>The GH docs had pulled all sorts of lead from Major, but there was still the matter of the bullet in Major‘s <i>heart</i>.  Yes, normally a slug from a Parker-issued K-38 in the ticker is going to put you down for good.  But this one found its place there in an unsual way; one of those bullets to the abdomen apparently passed through the liver, entered a large vein and was pumped into the upper right chamber of the heart, passed through the valve to the lower left chamber, an in that ventricle there it sat.  Apparently you can‘t just leave well enough alone, so someone had to go in and get the damn thing.</p>
<p>Enter Drs. <a href="http://ats.ctsnetjournals.org/cgi/content/full/66/6/2132" title="lymanplace" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lyman Brewer</a> and Ellsworth Wareham, of the <a href="http://www.whitememorial.com/about/history/index.php" title="CME" target="_blank" rel="noopener">College of Medical Evangelists</a>.  They‘d removed plenty of bullets from hearts using the old “closed-heart method,” but here thought they‘d try something new–having a heart-lung machine on hand, they thought they‘d throw that into the mix.  No more working without seeing what you‘re doing:  with the heart-lung machine, the heart could be drained of blood, and the surgeon can see and feel what‘s transpiring.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.llu.edu/news/today/mar0404/mc.html#1" title="DrJoan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Joan Coggin</a>, who assisted, also noted that they‘ve established a new approach to heart surgery in that they incised the heart on the underside, and not in the front; the electrical pattern of the heart, as evidenced by their electrocardiogram, has shown that this method results in far less serious consequence to the heart during surgery.  </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3305/3208042477_3a44ef660b_o.gif" alt="ellsworthandpals" height="534" width="300" /></p>
<p>
All this medical breakthrough, and all because some liquored Canuck on Bunker Hill decided to blast away at the heat!  Should you wish to know more about this miracle of science, why don‘t you <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sn/tvradio/programmes/horizon/broadband/tx/101/tips/" title="askEllsworth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ask Ellsworth</a>?  </p>
<p>A bit on the Hotel Rollin, as long as we‘re here.  Its building permits are issued July 9, 1904.  Its two and three room suites are each furnished with bath and kitchen.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3494/3208042179_e3d4fc4710_o.gif" alt="oldmanriver" height="443" width="575" /></p>
<p>Those of you with the eagle eye will notice the <a href="/StRegis" title="BozandtheReg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bozwell and St. Regis</a> just in the background:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3484/3208890126_58ba015da5_o.gif" alt="stregis" align="left" height="383" width="228" /><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3419/3208042387_bb717ebd8e_o.gif" alt="rollingrapestreetmap" align="right" height="424" width="271" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>(Of course, the Hotel Rollin had a musical combo that entertained guests, and to this day many people remember <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GBeRmjDrxXM" title="rollinsband" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Rollin‘s band</a>.)</p>
<p><i>Hotel Rollin image, USC Digital Archives </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/hotelrollin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Musical Cure and the Dead Girl &#8211; 240 South Grand</title>
		<link>/emmcurative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 09:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[200 Block Grand Ave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[200 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 240 South Grand Avenue Date: September 14, 1904 For about a year, from summer 1902 to spring 1903, Broadway strollers might hear exquisite sounds of healing emerging from the windows at 529 South Broadway, where the &#34;skilled physicians&#34; of The E. M. M. Curative Company practiced their pseudoscientific arts with electrical devices, x-rays, and &#8230; <a href="/emmcurative/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Musical Cure and the Dead Girl &#8211; 240 South Grand"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location: 240 South Grand Avenue<br />
Date: September 14, 1904</p>
<p>For about a year, from summer 1902 to spring 1903, Broadway strollers might hear exquisite sounds of healing emerging from the windows at 529 South Broadway, where the &quot;skilled physicians&quot; of The E. M. M. Curative Company practiced their pseudoscientific arts with electrical devices, x-rays, and gizmos that gave off heat, light, musical waves and faradic emanations (gals, you may be familiar with these last if you own a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000K8ALI8/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook">portable massage unit</a>). </p>
<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3137/2988607499_e843db52b5.jpg" /></p>
<p>Standing for Electro Musical Magneto, and using a unique <a href="http://www.google.com/patents?id=P09hAAAAEBAJ&amp;pg=PA2&amp;lpg=PA2&amp;dq=%22e.+m.+m.+curative%22&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=U7gXmha_LR&amp;sig=lNXQzOsNp1N9wC9TOW1V7Hf0MXU&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;resnum=3&amp;ct=result ">patented device</a> created by Henry Fleetwood, this interesting agency regrettably failed to leave any evidence of customers satisfied or otherwise. Incorporated in March 1902 with $200,000 in capital stock, the company was run by Fleetwood, D.W. Stewart, Herbert M. Pomeroy, lon [sic] L. Clark and Walter Rose.</p>
<p>It was a partnership quickly marred by tragedy, with treasurer and medical director Pomeroy, 38 and a drug addict, committing suicide by morphine in July 1902, out of an overwhelming urge to flee the world of the living and be with his dead mother again. Pomeroy, of 950 West Washington Street, left a note to his partner and personal attorney Rose asking him to cover up the cause of death and to be kind to the wife and babe he left behind. Rose and Pomeroy&#8217;s personal physician O.D. (you can&#8217;t make these names up) Fitzgerald tried to honor Pomeroy&#8217;s wishes, but in stealing the body away to a private mortuary before the authorities were called so incensed Coroner Holland that he had the contents of the suicide note released to the press.</p>
<p>We next hear of the practitioners of Fleetwood&#8217;s methods on September 14, 1904, when young Frederick B. West, a physician who was formerly a prominent fixture at The E. M. M. Curative Company before relocating to San Diego, was arrested at his sister&#8217;s home 240 South Grand Avenue on a murder charge relating to the death of Isabella Camello, 19. The girl was alleged to have gone to West in San Diego to procure an illegal operation, the incompetent performance of which resulted in her death. West insisted that while he had treated the girl for a stomach ailment, perhaps with a vibrating wand that gave off flashes of light and musical tones, he had not performed an abortion. The case was not reported on further, leaving us just the briefest glimpse of the world of quack medicine in Edwardian L.A.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
