<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>insanity &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/insanity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 01:36:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>insanity &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Hollywood Comes to The Sherwood</title>
		<link>/hollywoodcomestosherwood/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 11:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[400 Block Grand Ave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[400 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Avenue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narcotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sherwood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bunker Hill has had many landmarks, but perhaps none so little remembered as the massive foundations lain at 431 South Grand many years ago. They were great concrete things, poured about the time of the Great Panic, or the Lesser Panic, and served as Hill touchstone and reminder of ambitious building projects halted by devious &#8230; <a href="/hollywoodcomestosherwood/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Hollywood Comes to The Sherwood"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bunker Hill has had many landmarks, but perhaps none so little remembered as the massive foundations lain at <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=431+S+Grand+Ave,+Los+Angeles,+CA+90071&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=68.98527,101.953125&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=34.051948,-118.253381&amp;spn=0.009031,0.012445&amp;t=h&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=addr" title="431sgrand" target="_blank" rel="noopener">431 South Grand</a> many years ago.  They were great concrete things, poured about the time of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panic_of_1893" title="GrandOldPanic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Great Panic</a>, or the <a href="http://thehistorybox.com/ny_city/panics/panics_article12a.htm" title="panictheyounger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lesser Panic</a>, and served as Hill touchstone and reminder of ambitious building projects halted by devious economies.  But L. H. Mills and J. G. Talbott have come along and said <i>fooey</i>!  We reject these in their totality and all they represent, and with that utterly destroyed the foundations and have, in the style of all that is great and noble of the year 1912, set out to build from the ground up the finest apartment hotel available.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3045/2619773022_0f8cf7c8e7_o.gif" alt="theSherwood" height="583" width="575" /></p>
<p>
The building is 75&#215;176”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> and contains 160 rooms.  Despite its vaguely<br />
French Renaissance air, it is named the Nottinghamshire-evoking<br />
<i>Sherwood</i>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3207/2618137049_bc2f89840c_o.gif" alt="Sherwhynot" height="220" width="350" /></p>
<p>The lobby is 50&#215;41”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, finished in mahogany, its inglenook containing a large fireplace.  Each Sherwood apartment contains a private dressing room with built-in dresser and mirror.  Whereas law stipulates the minimum space for apartment living rooms as 120 square feet, the Sherwood&#8217;s are 190; where the legal minimum for hallways is three feet six inches, Mills and Talbott see that theirs will be six feet across.  Just because.  <br />
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3245/2618137239_f3f4285de6_o.gif" alt="thatsabiglobby" height="319" width="500" /></p>
<p>In June of 1915, the Sherwood hosted the wedding of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0366742/" title="thegreatPC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">P. C. Hartigan</a> and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0366473/" title="bestillmybeatinghart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Peggy Hart</a>, in the apartments of their pal, Sherwoodian Mrs. Dick Ferris, and in the company of Judge Summerfield and many a jolly Hollywood pal.<br />
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3121/2619773064_652beb293b_o.gif" alt="thatlllast" height="87" width="350" /><br />
Soon after, however, the quality of Hollywood Type there began to decline.  Even in our TMZ era that abjures accomplishment and rewards reprobation, dag, that <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0941745/" title="HLW" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Helen Lee Worthing</a> gave society a run for its money.  And surely set Sherwood tongues a-wagging.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3118/2620005308_42339312b2_o.gif" alt="HLW" align="right" height="325" width="250" />Worthing was a statuesque Bostonian-by-way-of-Kentucky who”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d become a Ziegfeld Follies girl–the toast of New York, and lady-friend of a New York mayor, it was said.  Darling of the rotogravure section, it was then on to Hollywood, where she made pictures galore while at the same time gracing nightly Ziegfeld”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s well-known assemblage of pulchritude.</p>
<p>She”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d always had a tempestuous time of it”¦in 1922, after a Hearst paper described in detail Worthing&#8217;s New York catfight with another chorus girl–including a cartoon depicting the biting and clawing–she elected to end her life by swallowing bichloride of mercury.  Ended up in Bellevue.</p>
<p>Once in Hollywood she made the papers in more light-hearted ways; in 1925 she drove her car off a cliff and from there atop the roof of a house in Whitley Heights.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3025/2620005226_37bfba4d52_o.gif" alt="hlw2" align="left" height="350" width="245" /><br />
But her career continued to blossom; Mary Pickford called her the most beautiful woman in the world, and  <a href="http://www.illustration-house.com/bios/fisher_bio.html" title="HF" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Harrison Fisher</a> adjudged her the most beautiful profile in America.  In 1926–the year she starred with Barrymore in <i>Don Juan</i>–she demanded $100,000 from a perfume company that had used her image.</p>
<p>But 1927 was to change all that.  In April she was the victim of a violent beating, administered by an intruder, which left her with a broken nose, knocked-out tooth and discolored eyes.  And five days of delirium.  Her colored maid called Dr. Eugene Nelson, noted Negro physician, to see after her famous employer.  </p>
<p>And it was love!  They threw society”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s strictures aside (it was still forty years before <i>Loving v. Virginia</i> and eighty til <i>Seal n</i>”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><i> Heidi</i>) and set about on a whirlwind romance that resulted in a secret Tijuana wedding in June.  The fact that there was no intruder, and Nelson had to care for someone in a mad fit of drunkenness (or, more precisely, a drunken fit of madness) should have given him pause.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3241/2620005398_7fc74ebaff_o.jpg" alt="helooksasblackasIdo" align="left" height="241" width="135" />They keep the wedding secret but is revealed to the world late in 1929, after their estrangement becomes known.  His philandering, cruelty, jealously, and threats of confining her to some sort of institution are apparently too much for her.  </p>
<p>In 1930 she returns from a New York “Neurological Institute” where she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s been treated for&#8230;the blues.  She is outted by a reporter as being shacked up at the Mayfair, and she moves into an unnamed apartment-house; likely The Sherwood, as she turns up there in short order.</p>
<p>Divorce proceedings stretch through the early 30s: she complains that he beats her and drugs her and forces her outside wearing only her negligee; he replies that they didn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t fulfill Mexican residential requirements and, as they”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />re not therefore legally wed, doesn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t owe her monthly monies.  By November 1932 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s hallucinating that objects are being thrown at her, and is threatening suicide, and lands in the psychopathic ward of General Hospital.  The marriage is annulled in January 1933.</p>
<p>In June of 1933 she disappears from an eastbound Santa Fe train–it is assumed she jumped, or fell.  A three day search ensues.  Turns out she just got off at Pasadena, abandoning her bags and tickets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3024/2621722712_742b1486dc_o.gif" alt="sherwoodarrest" align="right" height="140" width="252" />On August 16, 1933, the coppers come to The Sherwood to collect Helen Lee Worthing on violation of her parole to the psychopathic department.  In a statement from her psych ward bed at General Hospital, Helen declared that she had been living quietly in her apartment, attempting to increase her income by writing poetry and short stories.  “I can”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t understand who would complain and have me returned here,” she said.  “I have only been trying to get a start on my own ability.  Incidentally, I have fallen in love with a man who has been typing my poetry, but that has nothing to do with this.”</p>
<p>If only the story could end with her returning to the Sherwood, marrying the typist, and living long enough to move into the Bunker Hill Towers.  But it was not to be.  </p>
<p>In 1935 she is arrested on a drunk charge in Venice, and can”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t come up with the $5 bail, or even the pals to post the bail for her; she spend ten days in Lincoln Heights jail.<br />
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3161/2621933808_6a4087d36c_o.gif" alt="error" height="400" width="143" /><br />
In September 1935 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s living in the <a href="http://www.childrensinstitute.org/about/history.php" title="BSL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Big Sister League</a> Guest Home, when she again takes poison, this time over unrequited love.<br />
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3074/2620900207_4463acdc87_o.gif" alt="nursestrangle" height="500" width="283" /><br />
In 1939 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s sentenced to five months in County on a narcotics charge–passing forged morphine scrips and carrying a hypo in her purse.  In 1940 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s given a year for the same MO.  (Interestingly, while in stir, going about her duties as a trusty in the woman”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s ward of County, only three flights below was her ex-husband Dr. Eugene Nelson, awaiting his murder trial–not only was he practicing without a license, having lost that–but he killed a girl while aborting her fetus.)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3022/2621723088_d35189fb00_o.gif" alt="checkup" height="339" width="500" /><br />
In October 1942 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s popped for public drunkenness outside a downtown roominghouse; she fails to appear in court for her hearing, but sends a note:  “I am leaving the State.  I do not feel I can get fair treatment in California courts.”  Needless to say, she does not leave the state.  Radio car officers were called to the scene of her beating by some “boyfriend” in her Centennial Street apartment in April 1944, and took her to Georgia Street Receiving where she was treated for half-inch laceration on the chin and a 1+1/2 inch cut on the back of her head; she does not press charges.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3280/2621015543_5c0ca25b9d_o.jpg" alt="uhoh" align="right" height="58" width="217" />In 1946 she”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s found downed and dazed at <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=W+Sunset+Blvd+%26+Portia+St,+Los+Angeles,+CA+90026&amp;sll=34.076585,-118.254368&amp;sspn=0.008549,0.012445&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=34.076585,-118.254368&amp;spn=0.008549,0.012445&amp;t=h&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=addr" title="thebeginningoftheend" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Portia and Sunset</a>, and examination fails to find injury or illness.  She talks vaguely of trying to obtain rest by “self-hypnosis.”  Uh-huh.</p>
<p>Some would see this as a red flag; others as the checkered flag&#8230;the race is over.  In any event, people will sit in the stands waiting for a spectacular crash.  Most of the time, the car sputters and dies.  It”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s just a matter of time, now.</p>
<p>August 25, 1948.  She dies of barbiturate poisoning, in a tiny house (1062 North Serrano, since wiped out by the Hollywood Freeway) surrounded by expensive scrapbooks bulging with clippings from her golden age.  Inside were penciled notes:  “I can”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t stand another straw–it would be too much.”  Say hello next time you”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />re in <a href="http://www.inglewoodparkcemetery.org/" title="youdownwithIPC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inglewood</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3223/2619181215_6c92d0b957_o.gif" alt="kaddish" height="383" width="251" /></p>
<p>The Sherwood is now occupied roughly by the back side of the Welton Becket&#8217;s 1981 Mellon First Business Bank, and some miniaturized version of a street called “Hope Place.”  <br />
<img loading="lazy" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3034/2619409996_08040c2f48_o.gif" alt="SherwoodTonite" height="266" width="450" /><br />
For anyone who may gripe that the majority of this page deals more with Hollywood than it does with Bunker Hill, believe me, brother, this isn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t the last you”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />ve heard of The Sherwood.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
