<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World War I &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.onbunkerhill.org/tag/world_war_i/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 18:42:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>World War I &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Annie Larsen Affair Comes to Bunker Hill</title>
		<link>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/the-annie-larsen-affair-comes-to-bunker-hill/</link>
					<comments>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/the-annie-larsen-affair-comes-to-bunker-hill/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 21:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Flower Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu-German Conspiracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World War I]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[July 10, 1917 A resident of Bunker Hill was arrested today as part of a secret indictment issued by the Federal grand jury in San Francisco.  Ladel P. Varna, aka L. Percy Ram Chandra of 318 S. Flower Street was charged with violating the President&#8217;s neutrality proclamation.  He was suspected of being involved in the &#8230; <a href="https://www.onbunkerhill.org/the-annie-larsen-affair-comes-to-bunker-hill/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Annie Larsen Affair Comes to Bunker Hill"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>July 10, 1917</p>
<p>A resident of Bunker Hill was arrested today as part of a secret indictment issued by the Federal grand jury in San Francisco.  Ladel P. Varna, aka L. Percy Ram Chandra of 318 S. Flower Street was charged with violating the President&#8217;s neutrality proclamation.  He was suspected of being involved in the recent <i>Annie Larsen</i> affair, part of a &quot;wholesale plot to assist the Hindus in an effort to throw off the British yoke.&quot;</p>
<p>The affair, and the trial that followed is too hopelessly confusing to relate here in any detail, but involved &quot;German spies,&quot; the Irish Republican Brotherhood, and India&#8217;s Ghadar Party.  The <i>Annie Larsen</i>, a barely seaworthy vessel, was loaded up with approximately 4 million round of ammunition, 3758 cases of small arms ammunition, 10,000 Springfield rifles, 10,000 bayonets, and 10,000 cartridge belts, and sent out to rendezvous with the <i>Maverick</i>, and transfer the cargo to the larger ship, which would then head for Southeast Asia. </p>
<p>But back to Bunker Hill for now&#8230;</p>
<p>A graduate of Delhi University, Varna had lived in the United States for about four years at the time of his arrest.  When he arrived in San Francisco, he operated a fruit stand that did enough business to allow him to save up his money and purchase some real estate around Berkeley.  Then, two and a half years ago, Varna moved to Los Angeles and took a job in a cafeteria on Fourth Street.  He lived in a room at 318 S. Flower with four other men, and spoke perfect English</p>
<p>Of the charges brought against him, Varna said, &quot;I know nothing about it except as the complain was read to me.  It is all like a dream to me.  I was in no conspiracy to violate the laws of this country and can bring witnesses to show what I have been doing ever since I landed.  I have saved some money, but do not like to spend it on a lawyer.  I won&#8217;t hire an attorney.&quot;</p>
<p>Varna had recently registered for military service, and said that he was wiling to go to war for the United States if he was called. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.onbunkerhill.org/the-annie-larsen-affair-comes-to-bunker-hill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
