<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>delinquency &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/delinquency/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 01:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>delinquency &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Tough Kid</title>
		<link>/atoughkid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 16:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hope Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delinquency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen runaways]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 336 South Flower Street Date: January 28, 1932 Raymond Seccord, a 15-year-old Vancouver runaway, flipped out in City Hall&#8217;s juvenile court today after being busted in front of the above address. Refusing to answer any questions, he upended tables, lobbed an inkwell out the window and bit and scratched four detectives as they tried &#8230; <a href="/atoughkid/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Tough Kid"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location: 336 South Flower Street<br />
Date: January 28, 1932</p>
<p>Raymond Seccord, a 15-year-old Vancouver runaway, flipped out in City Hall&#8217;s juvenile court today after being busted in front of the above address. Refusing to answer any questions, he upended tables, lobbed an inkwell out the window and bit and scratched four detectives as they tried to tackle him. Seccord sneered &quot;I&#8217;m plenty tough. I&#8217;ll probably hang for killing a copper.&quot; Suitably impressed, Judge Blake sent him to County Jail instead of Juvenile Hall, and we will hear no more of this plucky fellow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boy Burglar Nabbed</title>
		<link>/hoytbrown/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Olive Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burglary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delinquency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jewels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 330 South Flower Street Date: December 22, 1904 Above, Hoyt Brown in 1910 Arrested at this lodging house in the act of burgling was the dapper, notorious Hoyt Brown (aka Frank Carlson), recently sprung from the Reform School at Whittier, but still rotten. He was about 17 or 18 when, two Augusts back, while &#8230; <a href="/hoytbrown/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Boy Burglar Nabbed"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location: 330 South Flower Street<br />
Date: December 22, 1904</p>
<p><img src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2345/2514585923_c9014e0b1e_o.png" /></p>
<div align="center">
<b>Above, Hoyt Brown in 1910</b>
</div>
<p>
Arrested at this lodging house in the act of burgling was the dapper, notorious Hoyt Brown (aka Frank Carlson), recently sprung from the Reform School at Whittier, but still rotten. </p>
<p>He was about 17 or 18 when, two Augusts back, while working as a bellboy at the Hotel Lillie at 534 Hill Street, Brown he was charged with having liberated valuables from rooms there, earning notice from detectives as &quot;a sneak thief a grade above amateur at least&quot; and &quot;bearing the unenviable reputation of having made the biggest hauls of any local boy burglar in years.&quot; </p>
<p>Previously he&#8217;d been employed at the Hotel Savoy, and he confessed he&#8217;d made off with a watch and chain. But his biggest likely score was the Dice diamond robbery: he allegedly rifled the locked room of Mrs. F.H. Dice at the Berkeley Flats at Ninth and Main, stealing six still-warm diamond rings worth upwards of $1200 and numerous other gems while their owner chatted with a friend down the hall. Hoping to avoid publicity, Mrs. Dice hired her own detectives, and while a few baubles turned up in a local pawn shop, most of the rings were never found. Pawn broker I.J. Smith was himself convicted of a misdemeanor for buying two rings and sentenced to 50 days on the chain gang or a $50 fine. Smith doggedly gave the old gang a try, but came up with the cash after a few uncomfortable hours.</p>
<p>On the 1904 occasion, Flower Street residents had previously noticed Hoyt Brown hanging around suspiciously, and today he was found in the act of entering someone&#8217;s room. Arrested by Officer Hunter and frisked, his pockets revealed a variety of jewelry, including a wedding ring engraved within &quot;John to Deed. May 1, 1890. Dec. 15, 1901&quot; which no one in the house recognized.</p>
<p>Hoyt Brown will go on to spend his twenties robbing homes from San Francisco to San Diego, between stints in San Quentin and Folsom prisons. He next appears in the local record in June 1910, when he&#8217;s discovered lurking in the closet of Mrs. A. Maurice Low, a visitor from Washington D.C. who&#8217;s stopping at the Stratford Apartments at Sixth and Burlington. Chased from the room by the shrieking Mrs. Low, Brown became an object of interest to the neighborhood. The noise drew the attention of Leon Godshall, a skilled sprinter who was playing lawn tennis nearby. He tossed his racket aside and chased Brown for several blocks, then tackled and held him until police arrived. Brown would unsuccessfully plead insanity over this last pinch, but was almost certainly sent back to prison. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Red Light Raid</title>
		<link>/redlightraid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 09:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[300 Block Clay Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delinquency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hotel Clayton (Lorraine)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nick harris detective agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redlight abatement act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 310 Clay Street Date: June 15, 1915 The Redlight Abatement Act is now law, and the first establishment to be entered by crowbar, ax and the strong arms of police and DA&#8217;s men was the Hotel Clayton, formerly the Lorraine. The authorities interrupted a gay midnight dinner party and made prisoners of all 25 &#8230; <a href="/redlightraid/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Red Light Raid"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Location: 310 Clay Street<br />
Date: June 15, 1915</p>
<p>The Redlight Abatement Act is now law, and the first establishment to be entered by crowbar, ax and the strong arms of police and DA&#8217;s men was the Hotel Clayton, formerly the Lorraine. The authorities interrupted a gay midnight dinner party and made prisoners of all 25 inside, including some panic-stricken ladies who begged to be turned loose as their husbands didn&#8217;t know they were out. In all, 17 men and 8 women were seized.</p>
<p>Among those arrested, 75-year-old proprietress Mrs. Florence Cheney (held on $5000 bail for pandering and $2000 for contributing to her 16-year-old granddaughter Florence Emery&#8217;s delinquency). Florence is now in the hands of juvenile authorities and her mother Ella Emery is being held on vagrancy charges. </p>
<p>Also arrested were Special Officers W.C. Becker and A.S. Ross of the Nick Harris Detective Agency, both in the process of devouring sandwiches and claiming to be doing some investigating of their own, attorney Chauncey Gardner, who refused any comment, a fellow named Jones who had no trousers, and a number of people named Smith or Jones. All came before Police Judge Frederickson and were bailed at $50 each after pleasing not guilty, save Mrs. Cheney, jailed on the statutory charges, and the two detectives, released on their own recognizance.</p>
<p>When the place was called the Lorraine it was site of the murder of the notorious Nellie Buck, Hite&#8217;s shooting of his wife and several suicides, and seems to still be a place of notable ill favor.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
