<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pornography &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/pornography/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 01:36:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>pornography &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Hotel Elmar – 235 South Hope St.</title>
		<link>/theelmar/</link>
					<comments>/theelmar/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 22:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[200 Block Hope St]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[200 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attempted robbery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hit-and-run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pornography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shotgun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There was a place, once, a place people called home–the Hotel Elmar. Not much of a place, 230 rooms, built in 1926, facing a retaining wall, small matter of a 1953 shotgun holdup you”&#x2122;ll read about, sure–but you see, it was the people that made the Hotel Elmar what it was. The Hot L Baltimore &#8230; <a href="/theelmar/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Hotel Elmar – 235 South Hope St."</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a place, once, a place people called home–the Hotel Elmar.  Not much of a place, 230 rooms, built in 1926, facing a retaining wall, small matter of a 1953 shotgun holdup you”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />ll read about, sure–but you see, it was the <i>people</i> that made the Hotel Elmar what it was.  The Hot L Baltimore of its day.  Of its dope-addled, nudie pinup, shotgun-toting Postwar day.  Let”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s meet some of them now.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3195/2507376342_14b98a0599_o.gif" alt="TheElmar" height="449" width="575" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3169/2514463314_38edc47dcc_o.gif" alt="lewiscantlose" align="right" height="300" width="157" /><b>February 21, 1947</b>.  Our first resident of the Elmar, Ex-Cpl. Roy (Peewee) Lewis, 23, formerly of Joliet, Ill, is one of those war vets who came to Los Angeles.  Los Angeles, the promise of the good life.  You could become anyone.  Your face could be up on the big screen!  Plastered on billboards!  Peewee at least got his plastered all over the corner of <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=James+M+Wood+Blvd+%26+Fedora+St,+Los+Angeles,+CA&amp;sll=34.056802,-118.297606&amp;sspn=0.009031,0.014591&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=34.056802,-118.297606&amp;spn=0.009031,0.014591&amp;t=h&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=addr" title="lewislosthishead" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ninth and Fedora</a>.</p>
<p>Lewis and his pal Paul Allen, 19, of 647 West 98th Street, were up in San Francisco a while back, where they managed to boost sixteen machine guns from the <a href="https://www.sfarmory.com/history.php" title="armory" target="_blank" rel="noopener">San Francisco</a> <a href="https://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2007/01/13/BAG0INI8PD1.DTL" title="kink" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Armory</a>.  Back in Los Angeles, they went on a taxi driver-robbing crime spree.  Then they came upon an unusually hard piece of luck.  While motoring along they espied a man who”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d just parked, drove by and gave him the eye a couple more times”¦this tickled the cop-sense of the car”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s occupant, Det. Sgt. Elmer V. Jackson, of administrative vice squad.  He drew his pistol and held it under his coat.</p>
<p>Lewis approached, leveling a paratrooper”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s machine gun at Jackson.  “I”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />ll take that” were Lewis”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> last words, for though he was referring to Jackson”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s wallet, Jackson pushed the door open, knocking the machine gun aside, and Lewis took a service revolver blast to the face.  Allen burned rubber and Jackson emptied his gun at the fleeing car.<br />
<img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3157/2514463350_1c7e918cc6_o.gif" alt="csa" height="93" width="400" /><br />
Police found an Elmar Hotel room key on Lewis”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> body and they lit out for Hope Street, just in time to catch Allen leaving with his arms full of clothing.  Allen–whose upper arm was grazed by one of Jackson”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s bullets–said Lewis had persuaded him to commit the holdups after meeting him in a bar, and Allen had agreed since he needed the money to marry a 17 year-old girl. So much for their next planned venture, which was knocking over a store at Slauson and Vermont.<br />
<b><br />
November 14, 1947</b>.   Edna Grover, a raven-haired 20 year-old model, calls the Elmar home.  But it was at the home of photographer William Kemp, 1830 Redesdale Avenue, where investigators from the DA”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s office found over 1,000 lewd photos of Edna.  Kemp was fined $350 ($3,678 current USD) and given a 180-day suspended jail sentence, while our Elmarette was granted probation for her provocative posing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3119/2513638807_2c58054a79_o.gif" alt="speedspree" align="left" height="175" width="167" /><b>March 21, 1952</b>.  Martin Salas, 23, left the Elmar”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s confines for an early morning <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;saddr=S+Main+St+%26+E+5th+St,+Los+Angeles,+CA+90013&amp;daddr=W+6th+St+at+Spring+St,+90013+to:W+3rd+St+%26+S+Spring,+90013+to:W+2nd+St+%26+S+Spring,+Los+Angeles,+Ca+to:W+3rd+St+%26+Figueroa,+Los+Angeles,+CA&amp;mra=pi&amp;mrcr=3&amp;sll=34.047735,-118.249412&amp;sspn=0.009032,0.014591&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=34.051664,-118.250999&amp;spn=0.018063,0.029182&amp;z=15" title="wildride" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spin</a> this day.  At Fifth and Main he hit a truck and injured the driver; he had an argument over right-of-way with a parked car at Sixth and Spring, and another wouldn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t get out of the way at Third and Spring, and he had a metallic argument with another parked car at Second and Spring.  Undaunted, he piloted smack dab into an RKO movie shoot at Third and Figueroa (<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0045205/" title="sf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Sudden Fear</i></a>?  <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0044417/" title="bml" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Beware, My Lovely</i></a>?) where a motorist that”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d tailed him flagged down a cop.  The officer jerked open Salas”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> door, only to have Salas step on the gas, forcing the cop to run alongside until enough cops tackled the car and forced it to stop.  At some point during Mr. Salas”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> wild ride he”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d had a passenger who ditched in an awful (in every sense of the word) hurry–hair was found on the windshield of the passenger side.  Salas was booked on felony hit-and-run.</p>
<p><b>March 4, 1953</b>.  Jack Hodges is 26, an unemployed aircraft worker, and lives a stone”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s throw from the top of Angels Flight at 314 South Olive.  His pal Dean Coleman, 22, is in school to learn <a href="https://www.smcelectronics.com/tvrep.htm" title="imakemoneyinmysparetime" target="_blank" rel="noopener">television repair</a>, and bunks at the Elmar.  When Coleman isn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t in school, the two of them visit the local hotels.  With their signature sawed-off shotgun and a briefcase.  The only robbery Coleman didn”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t accompany Hodges on, of course, was the time Hodges robbed the night clerk of the Elmar.  </p>
<p>Coleman”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s money wore thin and he”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />d pawned his television repair apparatuses, and went shotgun-brandishing to get the stuff out of hock.  Unfortunately for Coleman, Hodges pawned a stolen wristwatch, which led police to an old mugshot of Hodges; a little police work later and Hodges was caught in a bar at Sixth and Hill, his sawed-off shotgun and briefcase found in his Olive St. hotel room closet.    He gave up Coleman, who was arrested while watching television in the lobby of 235 S. Hope.<br />
<img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3088/2513638875_0537a159ca_o.gif" alt="devilishduo" height="103" width="424" /><br />
Coleman, who studied dramatics before his decision to become a television repair man, was never meant to be a shotgun-wielding, hotel-clerk robbing gunman in real life.  “As you see I don”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t appear to be a tough guy,” said Coleman, “but I can act the part when the occasion warrants.”</p>
<p>
<b><br />
July 22, 1956</b>.   Elmar resident Frank Swope, 33, took offense at fellow Bunker Hiller Harold J. McAnally, 57–McAnally lived one block west at 230 South Flower–buying a lady a drink one summer day in a bar at 822 West Third Street.  So Swope walked up and pushed McAnally from his stool, whereupon McAnally landed head-first on the concrete floor.  A few hours after McAnally died from his skull fracture, Swope surrendered to authorities at the Elmar.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3294/2511642636_ea63a9e693_o.gif" alt="drinkofdeath" height="178" width="182" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3038/2510811993_6d67f960c9_o.gif" alt="swoped" height="550" width="296" /></p>
<p><b><br />
February 7, 1957</b>.  LAPD went to investigate a disturbance in a bar at 731 West Third and there arrested “Allan Ayers,” 32, a resident of the Elmar&#8230;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3165/2515043102_d57d7d7d3a_o.gif" alt="gerberbaby" height="118" width="198" /></p>
<p>&#8230;turns out our Elmaree was in reality August Gerbitz, two years on the lam from a double murder rap in Evansville, where in December 1954 he gunned down his girlfriend, Mrs. Nadine Martin, 21, and one George Temme, 38.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2028/2515043124_03c0266703_o.gif" alt="jimfix" align="right" height="178" width="198" /><b><br />
March 20, 1957</b>.  Salvador Perez and Jesus Cruz, both 27, had been popped by narco and were up on the fourth floor of Police Administration, having been photographed at the lab.  They were walked into the hallway by officers Hernandez and Ruddell to be cuffed and led to the first-floor Central Jail for booking.</p>
<p>That”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s when both of them made a break for it.  Cruz, of 4923 Gratian Street, was tackled by Ruddell right out of the gate.  Perez, he of 235 South Hope, dashed down the stairway.  Officer Hernandez slipped and fell, broke his ankle, but continued to give chase nevertheless.  Perez ran down to the ground level and made a wrong turn toward Central Jail, turned and ran past Hernandez, but unfortunately, into the arms of Lt. Arroyo.  Another vacancy at the Elmar as Perez (and his buddy Cruz) are booked by an out-of-breath, broken-ankled cop on felony violation of the State Narcotics Act.</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3044/2506432249_bc1d55752e_m.jpg" alt="elmarafar" align="right" height="188" width="240" />Kind of makes you want to check into 235 South Hope, doesn&#8217;t it?  Perhaps you too can soak up enough of its magic to place you on this honored roll.</p>
<p>Alas, the City has wiped Hope clean, and thereafter had it thoroughly disinfected, as one would to so much egesta on a cracked tile floor.  They have left us with the most barely readable of palimpsests.  Let”<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s take a look.</p>
<p>Hope Street had two levels between Second and Third; here, we are looking north toward Second, standing above the west end of the Third Street tunnel.  The Elmar was midway along the block.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2288/2507367418_beb0fc24b4_o.gif" alt="ElmarToday" height="279" width="575" />Today, the bilevel nature of Hope Street is five decades gone.  The Ghost Elmar floats roughly above an intersection made by a new street, named after a Lithuanian-Ruthenian <a href="https://www.ruf.rice.edu/~sarmatia/100/thompson.html" title="Kosciuszko" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nobleman-turned-revolutionary</a>.  I betcha Frank Swope or Edna Grover never woulda guessed.</p>
<p>The City doesn&#8217;t screw around when they want something bad enough.  They&#8217;ll move mountains, quite literally, to which these images taken across from the Elmar (looking south down Hope toward the library) attest:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3227/2507366896_9d3ce319d0_o.gif" alt="elmar1956" height="446" width="575" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3144/2506540297_f1da72ae7a_o.gif" alt="elmar1987" height="447" width="575" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2324/2507260060_d61c5a60aa_o.gif" alt="ElmarCU" align="left" height="395" width="150" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Elmar, gone, but perhaps now a bit less forgotten.  For this blog is a little like the Elmar itself.  Like it says on the cigarette pack.  Wherever particular people congregate.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>Hope Street images courtesy William Reagh Collection, California History Section, California State Library </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/theelmar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
