<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>catalina &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/catalina/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A Lost Neighborhood Found</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 01:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/cropped-Bunker-Hill-Leo-Politi-sketches-castle-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>catalina &#8211; On Bunker Hill</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;I Am Going to Bakersfield!&#8221;</title>
		<link>/goingtobakersfield/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 09:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[400 Block Clay Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hotel Clayton (Lorraine)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[300 Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catalina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gunplay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infidelity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jealousy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Location: 310 Clay Street Date: June 19, 1910 Jerome Hite, former bookkeeper at the Woolwine Motor Car Company, is a jealous man. He drinks to excess, and likes to chase his wife with a revolver. In an attempt to prove she had been faithless, he pretended to leave on a business trip to Bakersfield, but &#8230; <a href="/goingtobakersfield/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "&#8220;I Am Going to Bakersfield!&#8221;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/2405883570/" title="jerome hite and wife whom he shot at hotel lorraine by richardschave, on Flickr"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2044/2405883570_42371d905d.jpg" alt="jerome hite and wife whom he shot at hotel lorraine" height="500" width="158" /></a></p>
<p>Location: 310 Clay Street<br />
Date: June 19, 1910</p>
<p>Jerome Hite, former bookkeeper at the Woolwine Motor Car Company, is a jealous man. He drinks to excess, and likes to chase his wife with a revolver. In an attempt to prove she had been faithless, he pretended to leave on a business trip to Bakersfield, but returned to their room at the Hotel Lorraine a few hours later, saying he had forgotten a pair of shoes. But his wife was alone. He took the shoes and again &quot;left for Bakersfield,&quot; but returned later that evening; again, nothing was amiss. Damned stubborn woman!</p>
<p>His behavior frightened his wife, so she went to the room of proprietress Florence Cheney to hide. Hite pounded on the door and demanded she see him, whereupon Mrs. Hite announced that she would, but only if he surrendered his weapon. He went away for a while and came back, and when he knocked Mrs. Hite opened the door and said, &quot;Now give me your gun and we will talk.&quot; Instead he shot at her, the bullet passing through her raised arm and into her neck, where it lodged. Hite fled, and his wife, while initially thought mortally wounded, rallied at Clara Barton Hospital. </p>
<p>On July 7, Hite was discovered on Catalina Island, where he had obtained employment at the Metropole Hotel under the name Hal Reynolds, but was promptly dismissed for drinking on the job. He was arrested and brought to Los Angeles to stand trial, although as his wife was recovering well, it was hoped they might reconcile. But it was not to be–July 28, 1911 saw her asking for a divorce on grounds that he had been convicted of a felony (presumably her shooting) and general cruelty, and we cannot imagine there is a judge cruel enough to deny her her freedom.<br />
 </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
